Good evening everyone.
>> Good evening.
>> Welcome to the 10 horns part three.
We're so happy to have you here with us
this evening. I have to say that I'm
just like you. I know absolutely nothing
about part three. Absolutely nothing.
And I was like, "Didn't we complete
everything in part two?" He's like,
"There's more." So, I'm trusting and
believing that uh there's more. So,
we're excited to be here with you this
evening. And if you would please like
and subscribe to the Power of the Lamb
YouTube channel that you are viewing
from, that helps to get this content out
into uh the internet world. So, yes, we
are happy that you uh guys are here. And
for some of you, you're opening the
Sabbath Sabbath up with us here. Uh for
some, the Sabbath has not even uh
started. And for others, you're probably
like, "What in the world is the
Sabbath?" Possibly if you're here, just
because you were scrolling on YouTube.
Uh but we are excited to uh go deeper
into this study.
>> Amen. Amen. Um, I will say that, um,
like you, Charles, uh, if someone told
me months ago that I would be doing a
threepart,
>> Wow.
>> and I'm saying three-part right now
because
>> it was originally supposed to be just
one message and one study.
>> One has not turned into three. But um
you know if at any point I you know
someone said to me you're going to be
doing an in-depth study on the T horns
I'd be like what for?
>> Right? [clears throat]
>> You know it's
>> that's really not the the you know the
ten horns. The main thing is the little
horn right the main thing is you know
Daniel 7:25. So
>> the little I mean the t horns like why
would we do a three-part series on that?
>> Um and here we are.
>> Yes. a three-part series.
>> Here we are. Someone said they just
shared, so I meant to say like,
>> like, subscribe, and share. So, thank
you for the person who just shared this
on their on their Instagram and other
social media.
>> Yeah. Um, for those of you again that
have not seen um, part one
or part two of the T horns, I'm going to
strongly encourage that you go back
>> and watch it. Um,
it it will help set the foundation for
what [snorts] we're going to hear
tonight. And
>> um, it's, you know, kind of interesting
because like I said, last week when we
finished part two, I was like, well,
that's it. I thought that was it, too.
>> And uh on Wednesday
of
>> this week.
>> This week.
>> You just did it on Sunday. We finished
on Sunday and then Wednesday
>> and I was like, "Yeah, it looks like I'm
not done."
>> So,
>> I can always tell he's going into his
little think tank and I'm like, "What
are you doing?" And he's like, "I'm
studying this out more." And I'm like,
>> "I thought it was done.
>> I thought it was done." [laughter]
Um, all right. So guys, we're gonna go
ahead and jump in because we got a lot
to uncover tonight.
>> Um, so we're going to have a word of
prayer
>> and uh then we'll jump in. You have not
missed anything, Noel. So uh we are just
getting ready to start. So happy Sabbath
to everyone and um let's go ahead and
open with prayer. Tant, do you want to
Okay.
>> Pray for us.
>> Yes. Heavenly Father, Lord, we thank you
for this opportunity to come back
together this evening and continue to
study the T horns. Uh Lord, we know that
your Bible there's no end to studying uh
something. We can continue, you take us
deeper and deeper and even deeper. So
Lord, we're thankful to be here. Thank
you for everyone who has tuned in. We
just ask that your Holy Spirit would
continue to lead us in this Bible study
and it and it to be a blessing to all of
us in Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen. Um, so I want to say that uh this
presentation tonight,
um, we're going to hit on some things
that you probably have never considered
before and have never seen in this. Now,
I could be wrong and if I'm wrong,
praise the Lord. But you're going to
hear some new things tonight. Um we're
gonna trace history again as we have
been doing in both uh previous previous
presentations
>> and um and we're going to track it back
down to our very time. So it's going to
be important. You you learned this in in
in study one. You I think you got the
hang of it in study two. So just
remember everything we share always be
thinking forward
>> right as I'm setting the foundation.
>> How does it impact today?
>> Yep.
>> impact us today.
>> So um again we're going to hear some
very uh for me super powerful stuff as I
was studying this out. But let's go
ahead and go to the screen. Um, and
uh, we are going to begin.
There we go.
So, this is the story of the T horns.
Um, part two, I'm sorry, part three.
And we're going to begin
in Matthew chap 12
verses 43 to 45.
And you may be wondering why are we
beginning here
>> with a study for the ten horns.
>> And you're about to see something
absolutely mind-blowing. So let's go.
>> When the unclean spirit is gone out of a
man, he walketh through dry places
seeking rest and findeth none. Then he
saith, I will return into my house from
whence I came out. And when he has come,
he findeth it empty, swept, and
garnished. Then go with he and taketh
with himself seven other spirits more
wicked than himself,
and they enter in and dwell there. And
the last state of that man is worse than
the first.
>> Even so shall it be also unto this
wicked generation. Now, um I've read
this verse
uh many many times
>> and u I'm sure you have as well and we
typically hear this verse in the context
of
you know uh being careful right not to
allow
um you know being careful to have Christ
dwell in you. Mhm.
>> And that is how I have always heard this
verse. I've never thought any more about
this verse than than that. And I'm just
going to ask, how many of you are pretty
excited right now because you think
you're about to hear something that you
may have never heard before in your
life?
>> Because I'm saying, I've read this verse
in this way before and I've never seen
it in this way before.
>> I'm going to show you something.
What is the context of Jesus's statement
here? Right? What is he saying? Why is
he talking about this? Like it begins in
verse 43 and ends in verse 45. Right.
Right. And he says, "So shall it be unto
this wicked generation." What is he
talking about? So if we go back up uh
just a few verses
um
yeah just a few verses. Verse 39,
Jesus is speaking to the religious
leaders and he says this, "An evil and
adulterous generation seeketh after a
sign, and there shall no sign be given
to it, but the sign of the prophet
Jonas."
>> For as Jonas was in was three days and
three nights in the whale's belly, so
shall also the s the so shall the son of
man be three days and three nights in
the heart of the earth.
So let's pause for a second. And he's
now saying, uh, this is the verses
before.
>> Mhm.
>> The Pharisees are saying, give us a sign
>> of your, you know, your mission. And
Jesus said, the only sign you're getting
>> is my death, burial, and resurrection.
It's basically what he's saying. And
he's using cold.
>> He's talking about Jonah
>> in a belly of the fish.
>> Then he says this in verse 41.
The men of Nineveh shall rise in
judgment with this generation and shall
condemn it because they repented at the
preaching of Jonas. And behold,
>> a greater than Jonas is here.
>> The queen of the south shall rise up in
the judgment with this generation and
shall condemn it. For she came from the
uttermost parts of the earth to hear the
wisdom of Solomon. And behold, a greater
than Solomon is here.
That's verse 42. And then verse 43. Oh
boy. I'm sorry. I didn't have it up on
the screen.
>> No, I was going to say something, but
you were kind of in a
>> Yeah,
>> there it goes.
>> Okay. So, uh, here is verse 39 and 40.
Right. Then verse 41.
Verse 41 and 42. the men of Nineveh and
the queen of the south. The queen of the
south.
>> Why is Jesus bringing up these two uh
examples, the men of Nineveh and the
queen of the south. The reason he's
doing this is because the men of Nineveh
>> were not they were Gentiles.
>> The queen of the south, she represents
Gentiles.
>> So, it's interesting. Jesus is talking
to his own people and he's saying,
"Listen, this generation," everyone put
that word in the chat for me, please,
those two words. This generation,
this generation, put that in the chat.
So, he says, "This generation
>> is going to be condemned." And guess
who's going to condemn you?
>> Gentiles.
>> Gentiles are going to condemn you. You
who had the truth, your your generation,
not the generation before you, not the
generation after you,
>> this generation
is going to be condemned.
>> So, and then he goes into
when an unclean spirit leaves a house.
>> What is Jesus doing here? What is he
talking about here? Well, when he gives
the sign of Jonah, right, and he's
talking about his death, burial, and
resurrection, this ought to remind us of
the 70week prophecy.
>> So, let me pause for a second. Just let
me pull ourselves up. Okay, so there we
go.
Jesus is saying this generation because
this is the generation that has been
prophesied in the 70we prophecy that's
either going to accept Jesus or reject
him. Right? And Jesus is saying now
>> Gentiles,
the heathen
>> are going to rise up and and condemn you
>> because one greater than Jonah is here,
one greater than Solomon is here, and
you're rejecting him. When these
Gentiles when they heard the preaching
of Jonah, when they heard the wisdom of
Solomon, they listened, they obeyed,
right? It moved them.
>> They repented.
>> And so the the the context then is the
70we prophecy.
>> Jesus is saying, "This generation is
going to reject me and therefore be
lost."
>> So what does that have to do again with
this parable? Let me go back up.
Uh when the unclean So verse 42 is he's
talking about the queen of the south,
you're going to be condemned. And then
he immediately goes into when the
unclean spirit is gone out of a man, he
walketh through dry places seeking rest
and findeth none. Then he saith, I will
return into my house.
Okay?
>> So let's build a stage here.
Remember [clears throat] that God had
called Israel for this purpose in in
Isaiah 42:5 and 6. Um it says, "Thus say
God, thus saith God the Lord,
>> he that created the heavens and
stretched them out. He that spread forth
the earth, and that which cometh out of
it, he that giveth bread unto the people
upon it, and spirit to them that walk
therein, I the Lord have called thee in
righteousness,
and will hold thee, hold thine hand, and
will keep thee, and give thee for a
covenant of the people, for a light to
the Gentiles. Again, Isaiah 42:7, to
open the blind eyes, to bring out the
prisoners from the prison. and them that
sit in darkness out of the prison house.
So the reason Jesus
[clears throat]
has called Israel is for them to be
lights, right? For them to be lights.
However,
the context behind the 70 weeks is
troubling.
Um Isaiah 60:2,
"For behold, darkness shall cover the
earth, the grow and gross darkness of
people, but the Lord shall rise upon
thee, arise on thee, and his glory shall
be seen on thee, and the Gentiles shall
come to thy light, and kings to the
brightness of thy rising." God's God's
ideal was for the Gentiles
>> to come to Israel for salvation,
not for the Gentiles to condemn Israel.
>> Right. and being more. Yeah.
>> Right. Not for the Gentiles to to rise
up in judgment condemning
>> the very people he called to be a light.
>> The Gentiles were seeing that Israel was
in darkness.
>> The Gentiles obeyed God.
>> Right.
>> Right. Where Israel who had the light
>> was not
>> is about to reject Jesus.
>> Right. Okay. They weren't living in the
light. That's what I meant to say.
>> That's right. So,
let's track this then. You guys, I want
to show you something here. So, in the
book of Ezekiel 85 and 6, and here's
what I'm going to I'm going to ask. I'm
going to put out a special number
tonight.
>> That number is nine.
>> Now,
>> okay,
>> do not hit that number nine. Only time I
want to see the number nine
>> is when
the things start clicking.
All right.
>> Okay. when things start to go off and
you're like, "Oh my word,
[clears throat]
you just go ahead and put that nine." In
the meantime, you know, again, I'm going
be like, "Put a one in the chat, etc.,
etc." But let's read here is Ezekiel
chapter 8. And in Ezekiel 8, um, God is
showing Ezekiel several things. He's
showing him the the abominations that
are being done in the temple. And it
says here, "Then he said unto me, son of
man, lift up thine eyes now
um toward the way of the north." So I
lifted up mine eyes the way toward the
north, and behold northward at the gate
of the altar this image of jealousy in
the entry. He said furthermore unto me,
son of man, see [snorts] thou what they
do, even the great abominations that the
house of Israel [clears throat]
committeth that I should go far off from
my sanctuary. Now, what is God's
sanctuary?
It is his
>> holy.
>> It's his house.
>> Oh, his house.
>> Um Ezekiel 8:10. So I went in and saw
and behold every form of creeping things
and abominable beasts and all the idols
of the house of Israel portrayed upon
the wall round about.
>> Jeremiah 7:30. For the children of Judah
have done evil in my sight, say the
Lord. They have set their abominations
in the house which is called by my name
[clears throat and cough]
to pollute it.
>> To pollute it. So
here we have the Old Testament
sanctuary. It is the house of God and it
represents the the the house of Israel.
Um and remember now the sanctuary itself
was a foreshadow
of God's presence dwelling in the
individual.
>> So we could say the sanctuary would kind
of would would in would symbolically
represent a man
>> or a house.
>> It's a man and a house.
Which is kind of interesting because
when you go back to the parable that
Jesus gives when he says the unclean
spirit when he's gone out of a man, he
says, "Hey, I want to go back." Didn't
say to the man, but to the house.
>> Right?
>> Interesting.
>> I want to go back to my house. Mhm.
>> So, here we have in the Old Testament,
uh, the children of Israel are
committing all kinds of abominations and
they're polluting the house of the Lord
with their idols. Okay?
>> They're polluting the house of the Lord
with their idols. And then
then 2 Chronicles 36:14 says this.
Moreover, all the chief of the priests
and the people transgressed very much
after all the abominations of the
heathen and polluted the house of the
Lord which he had hallowed in Jerusalem.
And the Lord God of their fathers sent
to them by his messengers rising up at
times and sending because he had
compassion on his people and on his
dwelling place. But they mocked the
messengers of God and despised his words
and misused his prophets until the wrath
of the Lord arose against his people
till there was no remedy. Therefore, he
brought upon them the king of the
Caldes, that's Babylon.
>> Now, let me ask you a question.
Would you say that by Israel's actions,
they had allowed a demon in the temple?
Everybody put a one in the chat. Mhm.
>> If you would say that Israel's rebellion
against God in essence
>> is seen
>> by the very fact that there are idols,
>> right,
>> in the house of God.
>> Put a one in the chat if you're
following me so far.
>> Idols in the house of God. They've
allowed demons. Let's say a demon.
>> They've allowed a demon in the house of
God. It's just one right now. I'm
speaking symbolically. It's just one
demon right now.
>> But
they have this demon in the house.
>> Mhm.
>> And the result is that the king of the
Caldes that is Babylon is now going to
come and destroy Jerusalem. So we read
in Jeremiah Jeremiah 52:13 that they
burned the house of the Lord and the
king's house and all the houses of
Jerusalem and all the houses of the
great men burned he with fire. And then
I want you to watch this. In Daniel 1:2,
the Bible says, "And the Lord gave
Jehoakim, king of Judah, into his hand
with part of the vessels of the house of
God, which he carried into the land of
Shinar to the house of his gods. And he
brought the vessels into the treasure
treasure house of his god. So then
in order for Babylon, a pagan nation,
>> to get the treasures of the house of
God, they had to go into the house of
God. Everybody put a five in the chat if
that makes sense.
>> In other words, think of it like this.
Only the priests could don't could go
into the house of God.
for pagans to go into the house of God
would have been an abomination. Right?
Everybody put that word in the chat for
me, please. Abomination.
>> It would have been an abomination. And
we thus understand that in order for
Babylon to get a hold of these vessels,
they had to be in the temple.
>> Okay?
>> Remember, the temple is destroyed.
They're in the temple. Now, why did they
get in the temple? Let's read in Ezekiel
10 18 and 19 because this is one chapter
over. So, we read Ezekiel 8. We skipped
Ezekiel 9. We're now in Ezekiel 10. The
Bible says here, "Then the glory of the
Lord of the Lord departed from off the
threshold of the house and stood over
the cherubams. And the cherubams lifted
up their wings and mounted up from the
earth in my sight." In Ezekiel chapter
10 verse 18 and 19. What the Bible is
describing here
is
the glory of the Lord
>> leaving the temple.
Right?
>> The glory of God has left the temple. So
if the glory of God has left the temple,
what does that make the temple?
>> Desolate.
>> Of God. Thank you.
>> The temple
is desolate. Y'all put that word in the
chat for me, please. The temple is
what's the word?
>> Desolate. Why? The glory of God has left
the temple. Now, watch this.
>> Even though the glory of God has left
the temple in Ezekiel 10:9, the temple
is still standing,
>> right? When Babylon comes and steps foot
into the place where they ought not to
be,
remember that number nine.
>> If anyone is feeling that nine coming,
just just go ahead, put that number nine
so that I know you're tracking with me.
Babylon is a pagan power that enters
into the temple of God.
And remember, the temple of God is for
God. Mhm.
>> So here you have Babyl Babylon entering
into the temple of God. Why? Because the
temple has been made desolate. Why?
Because of Israel's own
apostasy.
>> They've allowed a demon into the temple.
>> And God says, uh, you know,
>> I'm leaving.
>> The house is the house is empty. I'm
leaving
>> now.
>> So they left a vacuum.
>> So they there was a vacuum. I I like how
you're tracking Atanti.
>> I'm coming back to that word. There's a
vacuum
>> and and this vacuum is because of their
paganism that drives the spirit of God
away from the temple and that allows
Babylon to come in and occupy the space
of the temple.
>> Okay? So, a demon's in the house.
>> A demon's in the house. Now, notice what
God says in Ezekiel 11:16-18.
Although I have cast them a far off from
among the heathen, and although I have
scattered them among the countries, yet
will I be to them as a little sanctuary
in the countries where they shall come.
>> And they shall take away the all the
detestable things thereof, and all the
abominations thereof from then. In other
words, God is prophesying
that he is going to bring his people
back.
Yeah, he's going to bring his people
back. Mhm.
>> They're going to get back into the house
and they're going to get rid of their
detestable things. In other words,
they're they're going to get rid of the
idols that brought about
>> their captivity in the first place.
>> All right.
Um Ezekiel 36:24, "For I will take you
from among the heathen, and gather you
out of all the countries, and will bring
you into your own land. Then will I
sprinkle clean water upon you, and you
shall be clean. From all your
filthiness, and from all your idols will
I cleanse you. I'm going to cleanse you,
and I'm going to cleanse the house, the
temple.
>> It's going to be clean.
>> Mhm.
>> Y'all,
are you following this?
>> A new heart will I give you, and a new
spirit will I put within you.
And so the Bible says in Ezra 6:21, "The
children of Israel, which were come
again out of captivity, and all such as
had separated themselves unto them from
all the filthiness of the heathen land
to seek the Lord God of Israel did eat."
Let me just pause here and say this.
How did Israel
get back to Jerusalem?
God brought destruction upon Babylon.
>> Right? In other words,
first their paganism and then a pagan
power, Babylon has entered the temple.
>> This is all symbolic, you guys, of that
one demon.
>> The children of Israel go into
captivity,
Babylon
falls, [snorts]
and simultaneously the children of
Israel are going to go back to Israel to
rebuild the househ. H
>> Zechariah 13:2, "It shall come to pass
in that day, say the Lord of hosts, that
I will cut off the names of the idols
out of that land, and they shall be
remembered no more." This is all that's
happening. The elders of the Jews, they
build it, and they prospered through the
prophesying of Haggi the prophet, and
Zachchariah, the son of Edo, they built
and finished it. So now, the house
>> has been restored.
>> Has been restored. It's cleansed. The
demon is out. You guys put a five in the
chat if you understand the concept. The
demon that was troubling Israel, that
was dwelling in the house, is out.
>> Praise God. The house is cleansed.
>> It is restored. It is finished. But
there is a problem. Put a nine in the
chat. If you know what the problem is,
if you know what the problem is. In Ezra
3:10 through13, the Bible says this. And
when the builders laid the foundation of
the temple of the Lord, they sang
together by course in praising and
giving thanks unto the Lord. But many of
the priests and the Levites and chief of
the fathers who were ancient men that
had seen the first house when the f when
the foundation of this house was laid
before their eyes wept with a loud
voice. Why are they weeping?
>> They're weeping because they're saying
something is missing from this house.
Look at what it says. Who is left among
you that saw this house in her first
glory? And how do you see it now?
>> Is it not in your eyes in comparison of
it as nothing?
But the Bible says in verse 7,
God speaking, I will shake all nations
and the desire of all nations shall come
and I will fill this house with glory,
say the Lord of host hosts. The glory of
this latter, how shall be greater than
of the former, say the Lord of hosts.
And and in this place will I give peace,
say the Lord of hosts. What was missing?
>> The shakina glory that was in the old
temple is no longer there, right?
>> The glory is gone. And so they're
weeping. They're like, you know, this
house is not like
>> Solomon's temple. Mhm.
>> But God says, "Don't worry because one
is coming who is going to fill the
house."
>> Mhm.
>> Pause for a second, you guys. Just pause
for a second. We got to We got to build.
We got to cook this slowly. Okay.
Um, do you remember in the parable that
Jesus gives where he says when the demon
is cast out and the demon's like, "Man,
I've been out of this house for a long
time. I want to go back." And when he
goes back, he finds the house,
>> furnished.
>> It's clean,
>> and it's swept.
>> But
it is what?
Empty.
The house y'all is empty.
>> The presence of God is not in the house.
And if the presence of God is not in the
house, then the house is desolate.
>> And whatever that one demon was in the
beginning will be nothing compared to
the seven demons that come back in
because the house was empty. Mhm.
>> The seven demons are like, "Listen, man.
We know the story of how that one demon
got cast out. If we get a second chance,
I'm coming back with my boys."
>> Mhm.
>> All right. So, let's go back to the
screen, you guys. Let's go back to the
screen. I want you to see this. In
Malachi 3:1, the Bible says, "Behold, I
will send my messenger, and he shall
prepare the way before me, sayith the
Lord, whom you seek, and he shall
suddenly come to his temple, even the
messenger of the covenant um whom he
delight in. Behold, he shall come, say
the Lord of hosts." And I'm just going
to stop right there.
>> This is a prophecy of the coming of
Jesus to his temple, to his house. Let's
keep reading.
John 1:11 carries the sad the sad
reality
>> that he came unto his own and his own
received him not.
And then we come to Matthew 23:38
where as Jesus is about to go to the
cross
as he's in the temple for the last time
>> and he's talking to the Jews and then he
says these words to them, "Behold, your
house is left unto you desolate,"
meaning abandoned, meaning empty.
Now, I know you guys are thinking,
"Pastor, what in the world does this
have to do with the T horns
>> and with the end of time?" Don't worry,
we're getting there. This is part A.
This is the foundation. We're just
setting the the the groundwork.
>> Okay?
>> Jesus says to them, "Your house is left
unto you desolate." Meaning, not that
it's destroyed, it's just abandoned.
>> It looks clean. Now remember, so Jesus
leaves, right? And in Matthew 25:24, you
see him on the eastern side of of the
city and he's left the temple. The
temple's now desolate. It's still
standing.
>> Just like in Ezekiel 10,
just like in
Ezekiel 10, y'all,
>> where Jesus has, I mean, the glory of
God left the temple, but the temple was
still standing. Mhm.
>> When Babylon comes to destroy the
temple,
it has already been des Babylon didn't
make it desolate, it had been desolate
>> because the glory of the Lord had had
left the temple.
>> In the very same way, you guys, when
Jesus leaves the house desolate, it
looks clean,
>> it looks garnished, it looks swept,
>> but it is empty
>> because his his presence is gone. It's
been rejected.
>> So, Matthew 24:15 says, "When you shall
therefore see the abomination of
desolation spoken of by Daniel the
prophet, stand in the holy place.
Whosoever readeth, let him understand."
Mark 13:14 puts it this way. "When you
shall see the abomination of desolation
spoken of by Daniel the prophet standing
where it ought not," standing where it
ought not.
Let him that readeth understand. Then
let them which be in Judea flee into the
mountains. And again Luke 21:20. And
when you shall see the Jerusalem
Jerusalem compass with armies know that
the desolation thereof is nigh. Wow.
>> So the abomination of desolation
according to to to Matthew, Mark, and
Luke would have been the Roman armies
getting ready to destroy the temple.
>> So think of it this way.
If the one demon
was Babylon in the temple because of
their paganism,
that demon gets cast out,
>> right?
>> Babylon is is is is ultimately
destroyed. The temple is rebuilt. The
house is furnished. And all they're
doing now is waiting for the glory of
God to fill the temple. But they reject
that glory, thus leave the house empty.
And Jesus says, "Hey, it's your house
now.
>> It's your house now."
>> So when the demon says, "I will go back
to my house
>> and I'm bringing seven other demons with
me. I want you to understand that the
Roman destruction of Jerusalem is the
seven demons."
>> And now you understand the context.
Jesus wasn't like, "You know what? I'm
condemning the Jews and I'm talking
about how the Jews are going to get the
sign of Jonah and then all of a sudden
let me talk about you personally any
individual you know if you give your
life to me and then you let the demons
come in and then the he doesn't just
he's not changing subjects and that's
how this that's how these verses are
always preached
>> it's always hey you know what if you
accept Christ and then uh you don't
Christ casts a demon out of you
>> converts you and then you don't fill the
presence fill your your presence with
fill yourself with the presence of
Christ then seven other demons will come
>> right
>> I don't know I have never heard this
>> and maybe it's me maybe you have but
I've never understood this
in the context of what the entire
chapter is talking about where he's
talking about listen y'all you rejected
me
>> here is the result of what's going to
happen when you reject me right
>> seven demons worse than Babylon
>> is about to come upon you.
And the condition that you were in in
Babylon,
>> it's going to be worse.
>> Is going to be worse. The state of that
man is worse than the first.
>> Mhm.
>> All right.
How are y'all doing?
How you guys doing so far?
Let me read to you again Daniel 9:26.
And now this is going to really jump out
to you because in Daniel 9:26 it says
this. And after three score and after
three score and two we shall Messiah be
cut off but not for himself. And the
people of the prince that shall come
shall destroy the city and the
sanctuary. Who is the prince that shall
come?
>> that shall destroy the city and the
sanctuary. All
>> remember when Jesus is about to die and
he says this in John 14:30 hereafter I
will not talk much with you for the
prince of this world cometh and has
nothing in me. M
>> it's almost as if he's saying listen
that demon that was cast out first
>> he's coming back and with seven other
demons
>> Titus John
the Roman armies
>> who is their prince it's Satan
>> right
>> Revelation 12 the w the dragon standing
before the woman to devour the child yes
it's Rome but it's Rome operating under
the control of Satan. So the prince that
was to come is that demon is the devil
with his demons destroying the house of
God.
>> All right.
John 19:15. But they cried out away with
him, crucify him, crucify him. Pilot
said unto them, shall I crucify your
king? The chief priest answered and
said, we have no king but Caesar. I want
you to understand the significance of
this. We have no king but Caesar
and then Rome is a very power that comes
in
>> seven times worse than Babylon
and destroys the temple and the people.
>> All right,
>> let me stop sharing for a second
and I just need to check on y'all. So,
>> how are we doing, y'all?
How are we doing?
>> Tracking
still.
>> Are we tracking? Still don't know what
this has to do.
>> I feel like Yeah, I say I feel like I'm
tracking, but I still have not connected
it fully to the T horns.
>> Yeah. Okay. So, just let me show you.
Remember Jesus's mission? Matthew 28:18,
Jesus spake and said unto them, "All
power is given unto me in heaven and in
earth. Go ye therefore, Tanti, can you
can you finish reading that for me,
please?
>> Okay. Where did you leave off? Did you
leave off?
>> Go ye therefore. Yeah.
>> Okay. Go ye therefore and teach all
nations, baptizing them in the name of
the Father and of and of the Son and of
the Holy Ghost, teaching them to observe
all things whatsoever I have commanded
you. And lo, I am with you always, and
even unto the end of the world.
>> Okay.
>> Amen.
>> So, this is this is the commission,
right? Mhm.
>> God has given them the commission to go
into all the world to preach the gospel.
>> That's what God's people, that's what
the Jews should have done, but they
didn't. And so now, so now,
um, there is, as it were, a reset.
>> God is now called, he's about to call in
new people. A message is going to go to
the Gentiles to go preach the gospel,
teaching all nations. Everyone put this
in the chat for me. Put these words,
teach all nations. Put that word in the
chat for me, please. Those words.
>> Teach all nations.
>> Teach all nations. Okay. So,
um,
we're back at our slides and we're going
to now see this is the end. I want you
to, in fact, let me do this just as a
recap so you all can see.
Okay, so
this is stage one. Um,
the parable we're just looking at, the
demon is cast out, the house is swept,
the house is empty. And guys, this is a
parallel, right? So, here's a historical
reality. Paganism largely removed from
the Jewish life after Babylon exile. By
the way, by the way,
>> I'm glad I did not forget this. This was
like the the main point. Whoa. What if I
slip?
>> Watch this, you guys.
>> You said, "Thank you, Holy Spirit."
>> Yeah. Thank you, Holy Spirit. [laughter]
Man,
>> oh, now y'all really going to be putting
nines.
>> Okay. After the children of Israel come
back into the house,
>> they're like, "No more paganism."
>> Right. They felt like
>> we are not
>> That's what got us into that mess.
>> Yeah. We are not touching paganism
again. Y'all put a five in the chat if
you follow.
>> They they did they never again had a
problem with idolatry.
>> Never again had a problem with paganism.
Like they were like, "Nope, never again.
Never again.
>> That is it."
>> So watch this. Are y'all ready?
>> Mhm.
>> They began to measure their
righteousness
by their hatred for the pagans.
They began
to measure their righteousness
>> by how much they hated paganism.
>> Okay. Nine. I'm getting nineish.
>> Getting nineish.
>> I'm getting nineish. [snorts] In other
words, they were like, "Hey, the more we
hate the pagans and the more we hate the
Gentiles and the more we hate everybody
that is not like us,
>> the more righteous we are."
>> Mercy.
>> Are y'all ning right now?
>> Yeah.
>> So to them, righteousness was we've
gotten rid of the pagan idols,
>> right?
>> We've broken down all the pagan idols
idols. Not realizing that righteousness
is not determined by, oh, I hate
paganism this much, but do you have
Jesus dwelling in the temple?
>> Mercy.
>> And in their mind, when Jesus comes and
he's like, "Hey guys,
>> love the Gentiles."
>> Whoa.
>> Yeah.
>> Hey guys, be righteous. Hold on. Our
righteousness is our hatred for the
pagans. What are you talking about?
>> Mercy.
We we could stop.
>> This can go this this can be spoke and
I'm sorry to cut you off.
>> This could be what
>> this could you could preach to this not
just about the ten horns. I mean this
this spirit this thought can be preached
to different
and get different uh camps of
Christianity.
>> So she's already jumping ahead.
>> Okay.
But yeah,
>> the the nines are coming.
>> The nines are coming. Watch this now. My
hatred for evil determines
my righteousness.
>> My hatred for paganism determines my
righteousness. And this is what actually
led to the temple of God's people being
desolate. Mhm.
>> First, their love for paganism led to
desolation, and then their hatred for
paganism led to desolation. It's like
God's like, "Y'all don't y'all are not
catching it.
>> Y'all are not catching it. I want you to
hate paganism, but love the people."
>> They got it wrong both times.
>> All right. So,
so to recap,
to recap, God withdraws his glory from
the temple. Babylon destroys the temple.
And in a sense, this Babylon entering
into the temple would would serve as a
type of the abomination of desolation,
>> right? This is the unclean spirit
entering into the house and and as a
result of of that uh the children of
Israel in captivity. The house is
destroyed. God brings them out of
captivity. Destroys Babylon. Cleanses
the house. Hey you guys, you're set to
go. Everything is furnished. Everything
is cleansed. We're just wait we're just
waiting for the glory to fill the
temple. They reject the glory. Why?
because they were more occupied with
hating the pagan hating the pagans
>> as their sign of righteousness versus
actually accepting Jesus.
>> Okay, so
we are finished with part one of our
presentation. I'm going to stop sharing
the screen
>> now. Don't be deceived because there are
four parts to this. Don't be like, "Oh,
that part one was pretty quick." There's
four parts to this. So, but we're going
to do this. We're going to do this uh in
order. Let's see. Okay.
Stop sharing and
Oh, wait a minute. Wait a minute. Wait a
minute.
My bad, y'all. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Um,
I was going to the wrong screen here.
So, let me go back.
Okay.
So,
uh, here we go with with our second
part. Okay.
>> So, this is part B. So, that was part A.
This is part B.
Um,
>> so we're not into part two yet.
We're going to do part A, part B, part
C, part D.
>> Okay, got it.
>> Part two. This is part two.
>> Okay.
>> So, Paul says in Romans 12,
>> we're talking about the gospel now. Uh,
be not conformed to this world, but be
transformed by the renewing of your
nation
>> that you may prove what is good and
acceptable and the perfect will of God.
>> Right.
>> Except not right.
Because doesn't say be transformed by
the renewing of your nation. It says be
transformed by the renewing of your
mind.
The gospel is not a call to renew
nations.
>> The gospel is a call to renew minds.
>> In 2 Corinthians 10:4 and 5, the Bible
says, "For for the weapons of our
warfare are carnal and mighty through
God to the pulling down of strongholds,
casting down
statues and images
and every high thing that exaltth itself
against the knowledge of God and
bringing into captivity
every pagan to the obedience of Christ.
>> No, it doesn't say that either. Mm-m.
>> The weapons of our warfare are not
carnal,
>> but mighty through God to the pulling
down of strongholds, casting down,
>> not images, not statues, but
imaginations, and every high thing that
exaltth itself against the knowledge of
God, and bringing into captivity every
thought to the obedience of Christ. So
again, we see here that the purpose of
the gospel is spiritual warfare,
>> spiritual victory,
>> right? Spiritual conquering. For we
wrestle against flesh and blood. My bad.
For we wrestle not against flesh and
blood, but against principalities and
powers, and against the rulers of the
darkness of this world, against
spiritual wickedness in high places.
>> And then Jesus says in John 18:36,
my kingdom is not of this world. If my
kingdom were of this world, then would
my servants fight. So this sets the
foundation for us to understand, right?
And again we saw um we saw in Matthew
chapter uh 18 the great commission go
into all the world teaching all nations.
Right. Right. Not conquering nations.
>> Teaching
>> but teaching nations. Teaching nations.
>> Um there is a there is a portion of the
Bible where Yeah. Let me pause in that
for a second where Paul
is preaching and he's preaching about
the idols that they have up.
>> And he's not saying to take down these
idols, right? That's not what he's
saying. He's simply saying that these
idols are nothing, right?
>> They're not God,
>> right? They don't represent anything.
They don't they're not alive.
>> He's not on a on a mission to tear these
idols down, right,
>> out of the Roman Empire, uh or out of,
you know, these cities he's preaching
in. That's not his mission.
>> Okay.
>> So, [clears throat]
let's talk about the reset.
The first stage, Babylon to Rome. That
was the first example that we have of
your house being left unto you desolate.
>> Now we're going to go to part to to the
second example and it is this.
>> Okay.
>> So now we have the Roman Empire, right?
This is the early Roman Empire. This is
the time period of the early church.
>> And something you may not have under
known about Rome and maybe you did, but
in the Roman Empire,
in fact, let me just put it up on the
screen. Okay.
>> One of the most important principles to
the Roman Empire was, check this out,
y'all. Y'all ready?
>> Religious liberty.
>> Religious liberty. Let me go to the
screen and let me show you this. Rome
maintained religious liberty for all
faiths for over a millennium, hosting
thousands of gods. Christians were
persecuted within the system, but
paganism was the dominant spiritual
reality of the empire. I'm going to come
back to why. Let me read this. Religious
tolerance in ancient Rome. An indepth
examination written December 19th, 2024.
I'm just going to read one section from
this here. So, oh boy.
>> Okay, I'm have to do something. Uh,
yeah. Oh, man. I can't believe I forgot
this. Okay. The Roman Empire's approach
to managing religious practices in its
provinces was pragmatic and often
flexible. Rome generally allowed local
religions to continue provided they did
not challenge imperial authority or
disrupt public order. So you can see why
Christianity was a challenge for the
Roman Empire.
>> Right. Because where whereas all the
other gods were like you know hey
whatever let god you know whatever god
you want to worship.
>> Right.
>> For the Christian they couldn't have
that position. Right.
>> Right. They couldn't say hey we'll
worship the other gods and worship the
god of heaven too.
>> Right. God of heaven call for for have
no other gods before me.
>> Right?
>> So this policy of accommodation helped
maintain stability across the diverse
empire. So in other words, the empire
was actually an empire of religious
liberty. Y'all please follow this.
>> For instance, the Romans incorporated
various local deities and rituals into
their own religious framework. In Egypt,
the worship of gods like Isis was
permitted and even integrated into Roman
practices. However, when local religions
clash with Roman laws or imperial cults,
such as in the case of Jewish resistance
to the to emperor worship, suppression
would occur. This approach allowed Rome
to control its vast territories without
alienating its subjects, balancing
respect for local traditions with the
need for central authority. So in
essence what we're what what the history
of this
is that Rome remember Israel is allowed
to to do all their worship
>> right
>> in under the Roman Empire
>> they were living in an in an in an in an
uh in a place of religious liberty as
long as they did not oppose or
>> go against Roman law.
>> Okay. So why is this important? Because
remember the Christian church even
though religious liberty was in Rome
>> the Christian church was being
persecuted for 300 plus years right and
then you guys and then we have this the
edict of Milan 313 Milan I'm sorry
[laughter] 313 AD
>> Christianity is legalized persecution
ends
and watch this now you is
the only thing that the edict of Milan
changes is the is religious liberty for
everyone which would mean specifically
for the Christians as well
>> right
>> okay
>> so I'm going to read
again [clears throat]
this is from uh at Jones and we read
this in our last study but I think we
need to read it again he's about to
describe what the edict of Milan of I'm
is going to of Milan um was actually
what it caused when it happened. So
watch this as one of the very first
fruits of this Constantine
was established in the ro in the
rulership of one half of the Roman
Empire
>> jointly with Leinius. He then issued the
edict of Milan reversing the persecuting
edicts of Diolesian of Diolesian and
granting liberty and full freedom to the
Christians to observe their own mode of
worship. Granting likewise of uh to the
Christians and to all to all to all the
free choice to follow that mode of
worship which they may wish.
Had
the edict stopped right there,
>> it would have been a perfect situation,
religious liberty,
>> right?
>> It almost sounds like Clint, the land of
liberty, doesn't it? It almost sounds
like, whoa, that's like what we have
here in America today,
>> right? Religious liberty for all.
But
you will remember that part of that
edict was about returning property to
all Christians.
>> And remember it is here that the
Catholic Church said, "Well,
if you're not Catholic,
then you're not really Christian."
>> Therefore,
this returning of property should be
strictly to Catholics and the Catholic
Church.
this same edict issued. Now listen to me
you guys because this is just stunning
and you may not get the stunning of it
now but you will you will later.
>> This edict also granted taxexempt status
for the church.
>> So now with this taxexempt status here's
what they they end up doing. They end up
taking this religious liberty issue
>> that is supposed to be for all and in a
matter of years they're going to flip
the religious liberty issue
>> to make it apply only to them
>> and it really begins
at least partially over money. Mhm.
>> The love of money is the root of all
evil.
>> So you got this tap this taxexempt
issue. Listen to me.
>> Oh, you have this taxexempt issue
connecting with religious liberty that
they begin to flip and say on one hand,
hey, religious th this this uh uh stuff
that that you're going to give back to
to Christians, only true Christians
qualify.
>> That's that was the beginning. And I
want you to watch where this ends up
going.
>> So,
[clears throat]
let me pull this back up on the screen.
Following the edict of of Milan, the the
the Catholic Church
asserted that only those aligned with
the bishops with his bishops were true
Christians. This interpretation
effectively excluded others who they
deemed heretics from benefiting from the
edict's provision, particularly
regarding the the restoration of
confiscated property. The church thus
began to dispute the right of
non-atholics to receive property of
funding by questioning their claim to
the title of Christian.
In 380, listen y'all, in 380
things have gotten so twisted
that the edict of Thessalonica,
Emperor Theodosius
one declares the Nyen Constantine or the
Nyine Christianity
the only legitimate religion of the
Roman Empire. And now watch this.
Paganism and heresy became civil
offenses. Temples were closed. Pagan
sacrifices outlawed. Bishops integrated
into into civil life.
>> Let me pause for a second. I don't know
if y'all catch the significance of this
>> because what we're about to see, what
we're seeing right here
>> is that first the pagans said religious
liberty for everybody. Yes, at first we
were like not for the Christians.
But when Constantine converts,
>> the edict of Milan is issued and now
it's religious liberty for everybody.
Everybody's happy. You worship who you
want to worship. You worship you, you
want to worship.
And in a matter of 50 plus years,
religious liberty is now
outlawed
>> for the homos, I'm sorry, for the pagan,
>> for the worshipper of other religions,
>> right? There are now civil penalties
>> for being anything else but
Catholic.
>> Yeah.
>> Are y'all tracking with me?
>> Mhm.
>> Now, I'm about to show you something
that's going to blow your mind. Y'all
watch this. Watch this. So,
where did I say that that edict came
from? Let's go back. Let me show you.
So, here's an edict, right? It's called
the edict of
>> Thessalonica.
>> Does that word Thessalonica
ring any bells to anybody?
>> Anything from the Bible, maybe?
>> How about
>> Thessalonians?
How about the book of Thessalonians?
I would like to read 2 Thessalonians
chapter 2 6 and 7
Paul wrote this. And now you know what
withholdeth that he might be revealed in
his time. For the mystery of iniquity
does already work. Only he who now letth
will let until he be taken out of the
way. So let's pause for a second. What
is Paul talking about here in second
Thessalonians? Let me break this down in
this as simple as I can.
Paul was saying, listen you guys, he was
saying
the mystery of iniquity
is about to be revealed, is going to be
revealed,
>> but he will not be revealed until the
one who letth. Now, this is going to
sound kind of crazy, right? But let you
think letth means like to let someone do
something, right?
>> But in the old English, let means to
rest restrain.
>> Okay? So what Paul is saying is that
there is a restraining power
>> that once this restraining power is
moved out of the way,
>> this is what is going to reveal the man
of sin.
>> What was that restraining power?
It was paganism.
It was pagan Rome. Mhm.
>> Remember, pagan Rome
is the thing that comes before pap,
>> right?
>> Now, watch this, you guys. How is pagan
Rome restraining
this man of sin, the papacy?
Well, as pagan Rome stands,
it is allowing
what?
Religious
>> liberty.
>> Liberty.
Now, as wrong as they are for for
persecuting Christians because, oh well,
you're not, you know, going along with,
you know, the status quo of the
government, they in fact
represented religious liberty for
everybody. Whoever you want to worship,
worship. just don't cross the
government,
>> right?
>> Faulty,
yes.
>> Mhm.
>> But a way better standard
>> than what comes next.
Because watch this. What in essence
happens is that religious liberty goes
from for everybody for the pagans
>> the bad guys.
>> Yeah.
>> But then when the good guys take
religious liberty,
>> it's religious liberty for us and not
for y'all. M
you have to do it our way.
>> Now watch this you guys cuz I'm going
some weird with this. Watch watch watch
this. So um in 391 AD
a pivotal event happens. It is a
destruction of the cerapum in
Alexandria. Mhm.
>> The temple of Saraphice, one of the most
famous pagan temples in the ancient
world, was destroyed by Christians under
Patriarch Theophilles with imperial
backing
for the first time. And I'm reading now,
this is from the book, The Final Pagan
Generation, Rome's Unexpected Path to
Christianity. It's not a it's not a
religious book. It's just tracking the
history. And I want you to note the
title of the book, y'all. The final
pagan generation. This is the final
gener pagan generation before
the papacy begins to take to dominate
Europe.
>> Here's what it says. For the first time,
pagans understood that talking about
this very attack on this on this on this
uh on this idol. Mhm.
>> For the first time, pagans understood
that Christian attacks could reach the
most permanent and impressive elements
of the urban religious infrastructure.
Christians now saw temple destructions
both within and outside of cities as a
realistic way to remake the religious
topography of the empire.
>> [clears throat]
>> In other words, what you're about to see
is that the Christianity that is now
rising
out of paganism or after paganism is
going to now focus on, hey, how much can
we destroy of pagan culture?
>> If I were to rephrase it, I would say it
this way. This is where you have the
beginning of culture war
>> in these Christians minds.
Hey,
the house
is no longer the the the church,
>> right?
>> The house is the nation.
>> The house is the territory. Mercy.
>> And we've got to get the pagans out of
the house
>> in order for God to bless the house.
>> Mercy.
>> So now over the next several decades,
you're going to see
that this early form of Christianity is
all about culture wars.
>> Oh, that's pagan. We got to get rid of
that. Oh, that statue's pagan. We got to
pull that down. Oh, that's pagan. We got
to stop that. And now they have become
obsessed with paganism.
>> Now, mind you,
Jesus is nowhere in the house.
just
>> their whole focus of this is what
righteousness is is destroying the
pagans.
>> Getting rid of paganism is the is the
you get you don't like pagans, you're
righteous, you're holy,
>> right?
>> God loves you. You are that is their
whole standard
>> of righteousness.
>> Let's look. Let's go back to the screen.
So, I'm going to do a little bit of
reading. Same book. The destruction of
the Capium was a momentous event, second
perhaps only to the Gothic sack of Rome
in 410 for the amount of tens attention
it received from contemporary sources.
In the same way that the sack of Rome
shocked an empi an empire unaccustomed
to questioning its military superiority,
the disappearance of Saraphus temple in
Alexandria highlighted the vulnerability
of large centers of traditional religion
talking about paganism
that had once seemed a permanent fixture
of Roman life.
And now you know what withholdeth that
he might be revealed in his time. For
the mystery of iniquity does already
work. Only he who now letth will let
until he be taken out of the way. Then
shall that wicked be revealed whom the
Lord shall consume.
Whom the Lord shall consume in the
spirit of his mouth and shall destroy
with the brightness of his coming. What
I want you to understand here, you guys,
is that it is no coincidence that this
decree to Thessalonica,
it's as if Paul
was like,
"Hey guys, I'm just going to warn you
of what's coming to pass, what will come
to pass." And what will come to pass is
that paganism is going to be decreed. it
is going to be removed out of the way
and in its place something worse is
coming. So watch this you guys think of
it this way.
The church and I say that in quotation
marks has now made the house the nation.
And in their mind the demon that is
supposed to be cast out
is paganism.
Y'all put a five in the chat if you
follow what I'm saying. The demon that's
supposed to be cast out of the nation,
that's the house, is paganism.
And so they're going to begin this work
of casting out pagans and getting rid of
getting rid of everything that is pagan.
everything that that that that reeks of
paganism that smells of paganism that is
anything hu uh that that is reflective
of anything else other than what the
Catholic Church believes.
This is how they will determine their
own righteousness.
but not realizing
that the house is empty because Jesus
wasn't in that.
The seven demons,
listen to me y'all, the seven demons
that now come in is the papacy.
Seven times worse than anything paganism
could have done.
Did y'all catch that?
Seven times worse than what paganism
could have done because the church said,
"Okay, we're going to cast out the
pagans." Why? Because God wants us to
conquer the nations. No, no, no. God
didn't say conquer the nations. God said
teach the nations.
And you don't do that by force.
So now, now the papal church
or the church having having
suppressed religious liberty for
everybody else.
Get out of the house. Paganism.
shows that Jesus is not was not in them
empty house
and who comes in to occupy the space to
sit in the temple of God showing himself
that he is God it is the papacy
>> right
>> seven times worse
>> Daniel 8:11 yay he magnified himself
even to the prince of the host and by
him the daily this is where we hear that
the you know in Adventism we have this
argument about is the daily paganism or
is it the high priestly ministry of
Christ. I'm going to show you something.
I'm going to show you something. Please
watch.
>> By him the daily was taken away and the
place of his sanctuary was cast down.
Okay. So what does this mean? In Daniel
11:31 it says this. arms shall stand on
his part and they shall pollute the
sanctuary of strength and they shall
take away the daily sacrifice and they
shall place the abomination that maketh
desolate. Is this taking away paganism
so that the papacy could rule or is it
taking away Christ's heavenly ministry
which was the tamid the daily everything
in the temple was about the daily well
let me show you let me show you
>> the council of a 506 AD
>> a major church council convened in
southern Gaul under the political
protection of Clovis
>> it standardized disciplined and legally
enforced how the mass was to be
conducted under nine Catholic authority.
So, let's pause for a second. Y'all know
who Clovis is? Clovis is the king of the
Franks.
>> And if you're familiar with the date
508, this is when Clovis, you know,
basically it is said he gives his sword
to the papacy,
>> right? Mhm.
>> Just two years earlier,
this council
literally says the mass is now law.
Now, I want you to understand that the
mass, it is an ex, it is a direct
counterfeit of Christ's heavenly
ministry.
>> It takes people's attention off of the
heavenly ministry and focuses it on the
priests on this earth. So, watch this.
In 508,
in 508, let me put up put it up on the
screen. Clovis one converted to Nyian
Christian Catholic Cath uh Christianity
in 496. He went to war against the Aryan
Visigos at the battle of Voui in 507.
And by 508, Catholic power in Gaul was
effectively secured by Frankish arms.
For the first time, a barbarian king
fought explicitly in defense of the
Catholic Orthodoxy at the urging of the
bishops. So beloved, watch this. When
you take these two things,
>> number one,
paganism
is is outlawed.
>> You now must be Catholic.
>> Right. Number two,
Clovis becomes the or the French the
Franks become the sword of the papacy to
inflict to to ensure that what they say
goes now is punishable.
>> Right?
When these two things happen, not only
do you have paganism effectively taken
out of the way,
>> but you also have the high the high
priestly ministry of Christ,
>> right?
>> Uh
eclipsed
>> by the Catholic Church.
>> So watch this. What are they doing? On
one hand,
paganism is removed, right? And on the
other hand,
>> Jesus, no, you're not the high priest.
We're going to corrupt every system in
the sanctuary
so that instead of turning the church to
Christ,
>> the church is now an empty house.
>> Yes.
>> There is no altar of there's no table of
showbread there. There's no altar of
incense. There's no candlestick. There's
no ark of the covenant.
>> The the priests are are people.
>> The house is desolate.
This is the abomination
of desolation.
>> It is counterfeiting Christianity and in
essence saying, "Hey guys, righteousness
is forcing everyone to become what we
are."
>> Mercy.
>> Righteousness is your hatred for
paganism.
You guys, I keep saying I'm going
somewhere with this. The mother church.
They're the mother church. Righteousness
is
>> It started here with us.
>> Yes.
>> And we define righteousness by the
removal of paganism.
>> It's the removing of paganism.
>> So on the one hand, hey, if you remove
paganism, great. But hey,
>> no. Jesus in the heavenly sanctuary. No,
no, no, no, no. Candlestick, arc of the
covenant. No, no, no, no. None of those
things that we are the church on earth.
Mhm.
>> And in rejecting Jesus while also saying
we hate paganism, they're doing exactly
what the Jews did
>> in the first goround.
>> Because remember, Jesus applies the
abomination of desolation not only to
the destruction of Jerusalem, but also
to what would happen at the end of the
world. It's a two-fold prophecy.
>> Let's go back to the screen. And I want
you to see this. So, the Catholic Church
now had a military. Bishops no longer
pleaded with emperors. Kings now fought
for bishops. Pagan Rome restrain the
papal system by granting religious
liberty to all. Once that restraint is
removed, a new power rises and that's
the papacy. And so you can see here 506
uh the council of act 508 defeats the
visos.
>> Both of these represent in essence what
it means to fulfill this system of the
abomination of desolation.
The seven spirits worse than paganism
is the papacy.
>> I'm going to go ahead and skip and just
come down.
>> We're going to get to this se to this
third part.
>> So, by the way, 2 Timothy chapter 3:5.
This is this you guys. This is it right
here.
when Paul warned of having a form of
godliness but denying the power thereof
>> in the in the uh Israelite example
>> where they rejected uh paganism
>> but but
also rejected Jesus in the temple
>> it was a form of godliness but denying
the power thereof
>> in the early church when they say hey we
hate pagan we hate paganism
However, also rejecting the ministry of
Christ and the character of Christ, it
is the form of godliness, but it is
empty of the presence of God.
Okay. [clears throat]
So, stage two,
the nation becomes the house,
right?
>> Let me come back here. The nation
becomes the house
erroneously.
The idea behind the church is we got to
cleanse the nation of the pagans
>> and in so doing which Jesus never called
for.
>> In so doing they they put their
righteousness in the idea of we are
going to abolish everything that is
pagan
thinking that that's what made up their
righteousness. Mhm.
>> Jesus isn't in the house and the result
is that what comes in is the papacy
seven times worse than what they were
trying to cast out in paganism.
>> Okay,
now you guys, we're getting to part
three. So, we've done part one, part
two. Here is part three. Let me let me
stop for a second.
Um, and
>> I know I'm jumping a little probably
ahead. Even though I don't know what a
head is for sure all the I mean but I'm
seeing it coming together.
>> Um but there's just nothing new under
the sun.
>> There is nothing new under the sun.
>> The enemy
>> new under the sun.
>> The enemy Satan has to be the most
uncreative.
>> He just repeats.
>> Yeah. Uncreative person that I should
not call him a person. Uncreative demon
that there ever could be because
>> he just is just Yeah. He's on repeat.
>> Yep.
All right, y'all.
So, [clears throat]
Oh,
sorry. Y'all give me one second.
>> And he laughs at us humans because he's
like, "I've done this before and y'all
still don't get it."
>> Yep. You all still
>> mercy
>> don't get it.
Um,
I'm sorry. I shared the wrong screen
again.
There we go. Okay.
So,
now
we're about to see
how this tracks,
how this
um
leads into our 10 horns.
>> So, here's what I want you to see you
guys.
In essence, let's look at the Franks at
first. Remember, there are 10 horns,
right?
>> And I'm just going to show you. We're
gonna like really kind of skim through
this, but you need to check this out.
So, here are the Franks, right? And I
want you to notice what the Franks do.
>> One of the 10 horns, the ones we just
talked, the first one we just talked
about, Clovis.
>> Um,
okay. So,
in 508, Clo uh the church council
condemns divination. Penalty is
excommunication.
Charlemagne who was also part of the clo
part of the Franks 785. His cap capitile
deartibus saxoni outlaws outlaws all
pagan practices. The penalty is death.
Remaining unbaptized
death. Pagan rights
all capital offenses.
Just pause for a second.
Remember how we say the t horns are a
reflection of what the papacy was also
doing.
>> You have the you have the ten horns, you
have the papacy, but the ten horns learn
from the papacy,
>> right? They are converted and become
most of them Catholic in nature, some of
them aryan, and then we see two of them
become predominantly Protestant. Mhm.
>> So what I'm about to show you is that
you're going to see not only with the
Franks, the Visigots.
So remember record one, third council of
Toledo 589 converts kingdom to Aryan or
from Aryanism to the Nyian Cath
Catholicism and then decrees start
coming out. If anyone performs
sacrifices according to pagan rights,
let him suffer death. Fourth council of
Toledo, their children shall be removed
lest they be infected by their parents'
superstitions. Jews are targeted,
synagogues converted, festivals banned,
forced baptisms, children seized. Here's
what I'm trying to show you guys.
>> Their idea of righteousness, we can go
right down. The Anglo-Saxons, Alfred the
Great, embeds biblical law into English
law, ten commandments in the prologue,
uh, the council of Cleves, bishops or
ordered to forbid all pagan
superstitions and observances.
>> Um,
here's another one. Further solidifying
the shift towards Christian dominance,
the confession of Eggert outlined
several severe penences for practicing d
sorcery or enchantments.
>> While lesser magics resulted in fasting,
killing with magical filters, demanded a
seven-year fast, singling out women as
primary practitioners. Later, Alfred the
Great escalated these measures,
decreeing the death penalty for
witchcraft related offenses. So, here's
what I want y'all to see
>> in their minds.
In their minds,
righteousness
was outlawing
things that were not Christian.
>> No religious liberty
for those that are not following what we
believe.
>> Do y'all see?
>> Can y'all begin to see where this is
going?
I'm sure you can
>> these 10 kings yet are pawns as it were
>> of the enemy. They're showing here's
what Christianity does when it is not
when it does not have the power of the
Holy Spirit. It forces Yes.
>> It demands mercy.
>> It says listen uh uh uh you will be this
and we will make laws
>> for you to be this. Why? because they've
thrown out the law of God
and therefore they're now depending on
human law,
>> right?
>> To enforce righteousness,
>> mercy, policy,
>> policy,
>> righteousness by policy.
>> We see this in the Alamani. Stubbornly
pagan uh um uh St. Bonafice cuts down
the donor arc with Frankish backing.
Sacred space is no longer protected. uh
um the Frankish church state system
ended pagan practices in Alamina within
a century and we can just go on and on.
Suei, Portugal. Remember, we're looking
at all this not only at the beginning of
their rules but throughout their
history,
>> right? So, uh the Suevi, the
Burgundians,
uh the Lumbards,
>> and then the three out of all the ten
horns, there are only two of them that
don't religiously persecute. That's the
Herili and the Ostrogos.
>> The Vandals, they they the Vandals
persecuted Catholics because they were
not
>> Aryan.
>> So, it's almost as if it's showing that
listen, it didn't really matter what the
religion was. If they were Aryan,
>> you're not one of us. You're getting
persecuted. This was the spirit behind
these 10 horns.
>> Okay,
>> so we just got to pause.
We just got to pause for a second. So
remember now
in Revelation 11:7 and 8, the Bible
says, "When they shall have finished
their testimony, the beast that
ascendeth out of the bottomless pit
shall make war against them, and shall
overcome them and kill them, and their
great bodies shall lie in the street of
that great city, which is spiritually
called Sodom and Egypt, where our Lord
also was crucified."
>> So remember, the French Revolution is
what ends the papal reign,
>> right? Let me ask you guys a question.
What do you think
caused the French Revolution?
What do you think caused the French
Revolution
>> where the people hated
anything to do
>> with Christianity
>> with So watch this. up. It's not just
Christianity.
>> Because French Revolution was all about
atheism.
>> They were like, "Forget all religion,
>> right?"
>> So, I want you to watch you guys how the
process gets worse.
>> In in paganism in the early centuries,
the pagans were like, "Hey, religious
liberty for everybody." Mhm.
>> And then when the Christian church took
that over, religious liberty for us and
not for you,
>> they left such a bad taste
>> in the mouth of the people that by 1798
or by by the late 1700s, you have the
French Revolution is forget everything,
>> right?
>> Forget religion all together.
>> This is a result of the abomination of
desolation,
>> right?
This is the result of what happens when
Christians
when Christianity
doesn't follow God's word but says,
"Hey, as long as we hate the pagans,
>> we don't need the Holy Spirit.
>> We don't need the Holy Spirit.
>> We can accept.
In fact, listen, if you hate a pagan, if
you're not with the pagans,
>> if you're not with the king of the
south,
>> if you're against atheism and against
all the things that people who don't
follow the Bible, if you're against
those things, it really doesn't matter
how you live the rest of your life,
>> mercy,
>> will accept you as one of us.
Doesn't matter if you're really
converted.
>> It doesn't matter if you're converted,
>> but you accept all the
>> conversion is
>> legalistic things.
>> Yeah. Conversion is you are against what
we are against.
>> Are y'all following?
Because you guys, this
this is not coincidence.
>> But see what that produces me.
>> It produces unbelief.
>> It produces atheism. It produces hatred
for anything having to do with God. And
it's not because of the Bible. It's
because of the people who are professing
to believe the Bible
>> because they're trying to enforce things
without the power of the Holy Spirit.
>> That's right.
>> And then that is what is the fruit of
that.
>> We're going to convert the nation.
>> We're not It's not about the heart.
>> It's about converting the nation.
>> And you can't convert a nation. You
don't baptize nations like Constantine
did. All right? or or Clovis
>> army. Walk through the rivers. You're
baptized.
>> So, this brings us, y'all, are y'all
ready?
>> Are y'all ready?
>> Yes.
>> This brings us to Revelation 13:1.
because we've just now tracked okay uh
uh uh from uh Babylon from the temple
being destroyed uh uh Babylon destroying
the temple Rome destroying the temple
seven times you know Rome representing
seven demons worse than the first we
then saw the dark ages how now the enemy
is paganism for the church the enemy is
paganism and we're going to cast
paganism out of the nation but as a
result of taking religious liberty away
from everybody this is what forms the
papac Y
>> they're persecuting anyone who doesn't
believe as they believe and they are the
abomination of desolation. They are the
abomination that has taken the space
that has been left left desolate
>> by the presence of God not being in the
house.
>> This is this is occurring through the
dark ages. The 10 horns by and large are
following suit. You know three of them
are plucked up but the remaining seven
follow suit.
persecuting everything that is
uncchristian, ungodly in their minds.
And that's how they define
righteousness. Hey, we got rid of these
statues and we got rid of these all
these things that represent paganism
because pagans are the enemy
>> instead of what God called them to do.
Go out and be a light to the Gentiles.
They are instead being darkness to the
Gentiles. Mhm.
>> And now we get to Revelation chapter 13
where the Bible says, "I beheld another
beast coming up out of the earth. He had
two horns like a lamb and he spake as a
dragon." Now please remember who is the
horn that is responsible for Revelation
13:1.
>> Who is the horn that is responsible for
founding Revelation 13:11? It's not the
Franks. That's French Revolution.
>> The um
>> it's not the Visagoss, it's not the
Herili, it's not the Ostrodos.
>> The tenth horn.
>> Who is the tenth horn?
>> Anglo-Saxon.
>> It is the Anglosaxon
horn.
And this Anglo-Saxon horn, the Bible
says, uh, uh, it it it it's going to
form is the Bible says, I saw a beast
coming up out of the earth having two
horns like a lamb, but speaks as a
dragon. You'll remember from our
previous two studies all the different
attributes of all the ten horns, how
they all represented a counterfeit form
of Christianity. We're talking about the
the the horns as a system and not
individuals. Okay? Mhm.
>> The horns as a system and not
individuals. Now, why is this so
interesting?
Because this horn will ultimately come
to represent the king of the north.
>> Mhm.
>> Right.
>> Apostate Protestantism.
>> Which is going to combine with the
papacy. But ultimately, it is when Satan
himself appears
>> that they're going to defeat the king of
the south. So, watch this. In Daniel
11:40, the Bible says
>> that's going to give them power.
>> That's right.
>> At the time of the end shall the king of
the south push at him. We understand
this to represent atheism, the French
Revolution, and everything that atheism
has been pushing against Christianity.
>> But then it says, "The king of the north
shall come against him like a whirlwind
with chariots and with horsemen and with
many ships and shall enter into the
countries and shall overflow and pass
over." Mhm.
>> In other words, what we're being told
here, you guys, is that the king of the
north
>> is eventually going to remove the king
of the south.
>> That's the new paganism. That's atheism.
>> Watch this.
Remember that it was when paganism was
taken out of the way
that the man of sin is revealed.
>> Did y'all catch that?
M
>> when when when pagan Rome was removed,
paper Rome that that paper Rome took on
came on the scene
>> in the very same way.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> When Satan appears as Christ,
>> he is going to remove atheism,
>> right?
>> Paganism. And watch this. All who love
to hate the pagans.
>> All who love to hate. Oh, our war is
against the pagans. Not realizing that
God never called us to battle pagans.
>> God never called us to battle atheists.
>> He called us to convert hearts.
>> He called us to win souls.
>> Right?
>> He didn't call us to fight them.
[snorts]
He called us to win them.
>> And as as Christians are locked in on
the very same thing that the that that
the church in the dark ages were like,
how can we defeat the pagans? How can we
rip down pagan laws? And how can we get
rid of pagan fre religious li religious
liberty? How can we get rid of religious
liberty in the name of religious
liberty?
>> Right?
What you're seeing happening today in
America is literally almost like a
replay
>> of what the T horns were doing during
the dark ages.
>> Watch this you guys.
So remember now for the for the for the
second stage the enemy was paganism.
In the third stage the enemy is atheism.
And
just as there was a culture war in the
second stage, get rid of all the
statues. Guess what you guys? So we find
a culture war today. Do you know that
the Bible never called us to fight a
culture war?
>> Yeah. There is nowhere in the Bible that
Christians are said, "Go fight a war for
the culture of an earthly nation."
>> Nowhere in the Bible,
>> so when Christians in America now take
up this war, and there's a reason why.
Because if you want righteousness to be
determined by your hatred for atheism
and paganism, man, that's an easy mark,
>> right?
>> The more I hate, the more I I despise
the right, the more righteous you are.
>> Which now helps us to understand why
American Protestantism is so desolate.
Mhm.
>> It is because
>> for so many Christians today,
righteousness is determined by your
position against who you think the
enemies are.
>> That's very desolate.
>> That's a desolate standard of
righteousness.
>> But here we are.
>> That's not the Holy Spirit. That's not
Jesus. That's just not
>> Nope.
>> He It's empty. So, I want you to watch
this because the question is, how did
these culture wars in America begin?
That's where we're going next.
>> Okay,
>> y'all ready?
>> So, I want you to notice these
significant things.
In 1844,
um Darwin is preparing his um
>> his book uh the origin of species.
>> But it doesn't create a culture war.
And when I say culture war, I mean where
a political movement decides it's time
to get political with this.
>> Right? So people don't like Darwin's
book. Christians don't like the book,
but there's no political movement.
>> Mhm.
When the Scopes trial hits in the 1920s,
um it's a battle against Christianity,
it's a culture war, but there's no
political teeth with it.
>> When
abortion
when the abortion uh um when abortion
becomes legal,
most evangelicals
don't even care.
They they weren't they wouldn't they
they they viewed this as a Catholic
issue, not a Protestant issue.
>> So what is it that begins what we now
call the religious right?
Let me let me show you. Um and I'm going
to do something here, you guys.
I'm going to play a video. Uh and I got
to pull it up because I thought I had it
in my notes. Um, but I don't. Let me do
this.
>> I got to open up.
>> Just got a little glimpse. [laughter]
>> You just got a little glimpse.
>> I got a little glimpse. Yes. Wow.
>> Um,
where are you? Hold on, guys. Hold on.
Just give me one second. Okay. One un
moment.
Mercy.
Yeah, I don't want to explain it. I just
want to find the video.
Um Oh, man.
I know what I'll do. I know what I'll
do. Hold on a second. Okay,
>> Tante, would would you like to make any
comments
>> while I pull this thing up?
>> Um, I'm just processing. Um, but I think
>> and I have it now, so I I think I can
play it.
>> Okay. I was just going to say that and
this is I've said it a million I don't
say a million that's that's a total
exaggeration but many many many times um
>> um on well really on our on our on our
church during church I've said it that
getting a PhD in the character of God
will help you avoid
>> all all things that God does not well it
helps you know about his character will
help you know what his will is and what
he's behind. Yeah.
>> And when you find yourself hating,
because you're talking about
>> you're righteous if you hate,
>> it's so far from the character of God.
>> That
if you had better wisdom and
understanding, you would never want to
to follow that path.
>> Correct?
>> So, that's really that's really too bad.
>> Here we go, you guys. You're about to
see the reason,
the official start of what we call the
religious right. Let me show you. Um,
okay. Let me know if you guys can hear
this. Okay.
Another important moment, one that
started with a conservative political
strategist named Paul Hyrick.
>> We will truly see a moral majority in
America.
>> Hyrick had been trying to mobilize
evangelical voters and has said in many
occasions including to me personally he
said I tried everything to get them
involved in politics I tried abortion
issue I tried women's rights issue I
tried pornography nothing got their
attention that is the
>> historian Randall Balmer points to
another important moment one that
started with a conservative political
strategist named Paul Irick
>> we will truly
a moral majority in America.
>> Huick had been trying to mobilize
evangelical voters and he said in many
occasions, including to me personally,
he said, "I tried everything to get them
involved in politics. I tried the
abortion issue. I tried the women's
rights issue. I
All right, you guys. You guys,
>> I see that um you may not have been able
to hear. Was that correct?
>> Some No, some did because they quoted it
in the chat.
>> Yeah, I saw some of you saying you heard
and then you said you couldn't hear.
>> It's not in real time. So, we're not
it's not they're not hearing now.
>> Yeah. But can you hear us? Just put a
one in the chat if you can hear us.
>> Like they can't hear us.
Our mics are on. Okay. They can't hear
us.
Mercy.
>> All right.
>> Are they saying they couldn't hear the
Hey guys, be So, if you can hear us
talking right now, put a two. If you
didn't hear the video, put a one.
You guys, hold on one second. Here's
what I'm going to do.
>> Some heard because they were able to
quote it.
>> Yeah. Um,
yeah. Just give me a second. I'm trying
to pull it up.
>> There's a lot.
>> Yeah.
All right, you guys. My bad. Um,
it was a video that you couldn't hear.
I'm gonna try one more time. Okay,
I'm going to try it one more time and
I'm going to see if uh we can get it. I
think I know what I'm going to do. So
let me do This
After
courts ruled that schools that
discriminate weren't entitled to tax
exemption exempt from the IRS IRS
Internal Revenue Service proposed to
make [music] private schools prove they
are not practicing racial discrimination
or lose their tax exempt status. Only
then according to Wy that evangelicals
became interested in
>> All right. So that
>> was pretty bad, Joe. That was pretty
bad. Pretty bad. Pretty bad. We're sorry
you
>> We're sorry. You could hear it now.
>> Well, they could hear us now.
>> Let me just let me explain what's going
on. Okay.
>> I heard it with the feedback cuz
>> Yeah, you heard it with the feedback. So
basically what he was saying was that
Paul Hayrick was trying to use
everything he could to galvanize a
political movement that would uh you
know basically garner the support of
Christians in America
>> to create a voting block that would
basically help to to make Christianity a
national like
>> like a national
>> Christian nationalism,
>> right?
And he said everything that he tried,
abortion,
um, homosexuality, everything he tried
failed with one exception. And the one
exception is when their taxexempt
status
>> of segregated Christian schools was
challenged.
>> I'll put the link
>> in the chat.
>> When their tax now, what did I just say?
the taxexempt
>> status.
>> Remember what it was way back there when
the when the church was like, "Hold on.
We're going to take advantage of this
opportunity for ourselves,
>> right?
>> You can't make this up."
>> Now, I want you to remember this.
Yeah, I hear it.
>> Okay, I [clears throat] want you to
remember this.
It was as if these two things combined,
the tax exempt status
>> and you're trying to make us
mingle
with people who are not like us.
These are the two things that start the
political movement of the religious
right. Mhm.
>> Money
>> and racism
>> and racism,
>> mercy,
>> which really makes sense when you think
about the history that the Bible is
showing us regarding these ten horns
>> for the schools or for the churches? For
the Christian schools.
>> For the schools.
>> You can't tell us. If we start our own
Christian schools, we'll get t we'll get
tax exemptions.
>> You guys, y'all not going to hear this.
You're not going to hear this,
>> but the whole Christian homeschool
movement
>> mercy.
>> Now, I'm not saying there's something
wrong with the Christian homeschool
movement.
>> I'm just saying that it started because
of this. It wanted to I've heard I've
heard it had to be you, but I've heard
you say this before, but not like this,
but I've heard I heard that from you
before. Um, but
so just slow it down.
>> We're not going to send our kids to
school to integrated schools. We're
going to form our own school,
>> Christian school. Yes, that's what I've
heard you say before.
>> And then Bob Jones.
>> But you were just trying Yes. Yes. Yes.
Yes. Yes.
>> Bob Jones. That is the school that
kicked it off. Jerry Fwell, all these
guys got into this battle of you're
impinging on our religious because
>> liberty.
>> Wow. Because of SE for integrating
schools. So now we don't we don't want
to integrate.
So the only way that we can do this and
to be able to able to do it and afford
it better is to be able to get tax
exempt status. And so we can raise money
and do all of these things for our own
Christian schools.
>> For our own
>> for our own Christian
>> Christian
>> white schools
>> schools,
>> right?
>> And you guys
>> and you can't tell us what to do. And if
we want and we if we went
>> you're you're infringing upon our
religious liberty. So here's what I want
y'all to understand you guys. Again,
we're not talking about everybody. We're
talking about a se a system of
>> created
>> abomination of desolation
>> that says righteousness is who we are
against.
>> Mercy.
>> Righteousness is what we if we can
gather together on what we hate and what
we dislike.
>> Can I say this really quick? I'm sorry.
Let's just slow down. I I have I haven't
all talked that much for two hours,
which again is always that's always
amazing. But
this is a known fact. I mean, just a
little transparency. Um,
>> I remember
>> we homeschooled our two oldest children
>> and you were using Bob Jones. used Bob
Jones
at a not the whole time but there was a
period of time and I remember get
looking into it and it was like finding
out that Bob Jones was accused of being
racist and I was like why like
>> you know the the curriculum's good blah
blah you know all these things but um it
stayed w with him it wasn't you know it
it stayed with him
>> it's very interesting
>> yep
Very interesting.
>> So, so watch this you guys. Let me just
We're We're almost done. But when now
this is where the fire comes. All right.
>> Everything was just a setup.
>> That wasn't the fire.
>> This was none of this was the fire.
>> That right there wasn't the fire.
>> Yeah.
>> Mercy.
>> Here we go. So, the real birth of the
religious right was not abortion, but
segregation.
Core fact. The modern religious right
did not begin over versus Wade. It began
when the federal government threatened
the taxexempt status of segregated
Christian schools. So these key moments
1954, Brown versus education, uh
segregatedmies where thousands of white
only schools were formed, um Green
versus Connley, which is where the IRS
denies tax exemption to racially
discriminatory schools.
>> If you guys are Okay, we're laughing for
a whole another reason. Yeah. I don't
know how our cat does it, but he opens
the garage door.
>> Well, I think it wasn't. It has to be
just not quite closed tight enough. And
he works. And he works.
>> But still, how do you as a cat open a
garage door?
>> Okay. But I don't want to take their
minds off of this. And Tiger, you just
interrupted in a very important time.
>> 1976 IRS moves against Bob Jones
University. Um, a loss of tax uh of tax
exemption for banning interracial
dating. And this is where it begins,
>> right?
>> Wow.
>> This is where it begins. And so there's
a strategic shift. Losing losing co c
cultural control. They're now seeking
political control.
>> And so now you have movements such as
the moral majority, the Christian
coalition, Pat Robertson.
>> The alliance with the GOP hardens under
Reagan.
>> Religion becomes a mobilization engine,
not a moral corrective. You guys,
>> the moment this happens,
>> the moment this happens, we are seeing
exactly what happened during the T
horns. We're seeing exactly what
happened.
>> You guys know why Tiger went over there?
Because it's his cats and he loves him.
He doesn't ever try to He's not trying
to come over here by me. He's coming in
here because he wants to be Oh. Oh my
goodness. with with his owner. Oh
goodness. Okay. I We're disturbing that
and and Tiger is being used.
I don't know. Tiger, are you being used
by God or the enemy?
>> So, I'm sorry you guys. Um
>> you you couldn't spoil him and push him
off the he'll be fine.
>> So, the religious or religion becomes a
mobilization engine. Now, we're
literally looking at
>> the formation of exactly what has come
before.
>> Mhm.
>> Now, I want y'all to understand
something because the the the final
piece of this is that what is coming to
fill the house this time
>> is is worse. Remember, think of it.
First is one demon. He comes back with
seven more.
>> Every time this happens, it's seven
more. Symbolically speaking, seven more.
The final abomination of desolation
>> that is going to fill the house, which
by the way is why the Bible says Babylon
has become the habitation of devils and
every un every unclean spirit. This
final iteration
>> of these demons
really you guys, it is the it is the
three unclean spirits like frogs.
that will come in
and deceive the entire world.
>> But I'm jumping ahead. I'm jumping
ahead. We just need to track this, you
guys. And I'm going to track this in all
everything that we're about everything
I'm about to say right now is a
culmination of years of stuff you have
heard. Some of it is going to be hard to
hear, but I'm about to speak this thing
whether you like it or not.
>> Okay? I'm gonna let you speak it and if
it's going with the thoughts that I'm
that I'm thinking then that's good. If
not I'm gonna come back.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> So, for example, now you have Dominion
theology, right? And the seven mountain
mandates which started up in the 1990s
and the 2000s. This is this is a
theological upgrade. Now,
>> we're going to implement prophecy
>> to connect with our evangelical
movement. In other words, we're going to
now begin to prophesy that God wants a
nation that has turned to him. We're
going to prophesy. We know we can't show
it in the word. We're going to have
dreams and visions about Listen to me.
Who's about to be president?
>> Yeah. Mercy, mercy, mercy, mercy. We're
going to have dreams and visions about
how God wants to wants to take the the
seven mountains
>> away from the pagans,
>> away from the atheists. We got to
control those seven mountains,
>> God never put us on this earth to
control mountains.
>> All right.
Wow.
Wow. Wow. Wow.
Wow. Wow.
God never
called us
to conquer
anything on this earth
>> but human hearts
>> through the power of the gospel.
And so you have this conversion of
dominion theology and the seven
mountains ma mandates. We got to take
over government and media and education
and business and family and religion and
arts and entertainment. While at the
same time, let me just be honest. when
you're watching this removal of of of of
things that remind this country of the
racism that it once exercised and and
we're going to do away with with
diversity and equity all those things
you guys it's not by it's not accidental
>> not at all
this is what I want to say that you're
going there
because I don't
we can't it's not accidental and we you
can't I mean you can't just look over it
and be like oh okay it was racism No,
it's it is
racism that fuels this whole thing.
>> The T horns,
>> when you go back and look at the history
of the T horns,
>> they were all about dominion of their
territory. And as we go through these 10
horns, we begin to see with the with the
Svi, with the Portuguese,
>> with the with the um uh the Alamani,
>> um with uh Spain, we begin to see these
elements and the Anglo-Sax, we see these
elements of racial superiority. And the
last horn to to to dominate. The final
horn that's going to bring this all
together with the little horn is the
tenth horn.
Mercy.
>> And as we look at the tenth horn and and
you guys, it is not
it is not by chance, right?
>> Like we don't we don't just say, you
know, our president and first lady are
are monkeys by accident
>> and apes. Yeah.
>> We don't say they're apes by accident.
We
>> in in 2026.
>> In 2026, those kind of things are not
accidental. Mhm.
>> The whole talking of, you know, the
replacement theory and and all that's
happening with the im with the
immigrants. We got to get the immigrants
out, all the things that are being said
right now. Listen, I know that there are
that there are, you know, maybe some
people that have some concerns. What?
But listen, by and large, by and large,
the reason God is showing us what these
horns do and how they mingle
Christianity with their perversions,
>> if we don't recognize it, we're being
blinded to prophecy.
>> So, so watch this.
When you just think of things like the
Tea Party and their reaction to Hold on,
wait a minute. The first
>> And we thought the Tea Party was
radical.
>> We thought the Tea Party was the first
>> The Tea Party. I mean,
>> yeah.
>> They were nothing compared to this.
>> This nation has a black president.
Oh,
now guys, listen.
It's all right for the world to have
that kind of reaction. The world is
gonna world,
but Christians should Christians,
>> how can you be a Christian and have that
kind of reaction? Now, we want to make
the first black president that this
nation has ever had to be the worst
president the nation has ever had. How
is that? Like of all the presidents in
the world that that have ever ever
existed, the worst one, the one that is
that is that has brought in God's
disfavor upon the upon America happens
to be the first black president. Now you
guys listen, this is not about getting
political. I'm just trying to show you
that the things you are seeing unfolding
before your eyes,
>> the hatred for immigrants,
the open talk of
I remember when when uh when Twitter
became X
>> and
>> what they could say
>> that day that Twitter became X, all you
saw was wait, we can say and they would
put the N word. We can say and now.
Literally, it was flooded with
>> oh, freedom of speech. We can say and
now.
>> We can say and now.
>> You guys, when Ellen White says that a
race war would be repeated.
When she says that I saw that slavery
would again exist in the last days. When
we see that our pioneers said the
identifying mark of America at the the
beast with horns of a lamb that spake as
a dragon is primarily the the way we
primarily identify is by the hypocrisy
of the Christians in this nation
>> who say I love God but at the same time
own slaves. This should show us
everything we need to know.
Mhm.
>> And all of this, you guys, all of this
has led to what we now know today as the
>> Magistry.
The Magist.
The Magichrist represents power
>> without holiness, vengeance
without virtue, victory without
repentance. Mhm.
>> And evangelicals
embrace this this concept,
>> embrace
this system
>> because it says we will give you
dominion.
So you got prophets, you got a president
who says I will do the exact things that
Constantine did. Mhm.
>> I will make Christianity great again.
>> You have the political anointing.
You have all of these things going on,
you guys. And the the scary thing
is that among us,
there will be people who are just
blinded to this because they're going to
say, "Oh, this is political.
>> It's it's not."
>> After all the prophetic everything that
we've seen, you can still turn around
and be like, "It's political.
M
>> Oh, it's once you touch my golden calf,
it becomes political.
But if you're talking about the pagans,
>> watch this. Now, if you're talking about
the pagans and the atheists, I'm with
you all day long.
>> Because the pagans are the evil ones.
Mhm.
>> I mean, the only thing that would make
this movement come together is
integrating schools,
not abortion,
>> not abortion. They did not care about
abortion. They said that's a Catholic
thing. That's not our battle. But I want
you to understand. So now they're just
like, "Hey, what else can we do to
garner our, "Hey, you're against this.
All right, let's bring it into you're
against this. Let's bring And all this
is you guys is it is a political
movement disguised under religion.
>> Yes,
>> that's all it is.
>> That's all it is.
>> Just like the T horns, just like
Clovis's conversion, just like
Constantine's conversion. This is all is
all it is.
>> All the other ten horns are
>> That's right. The T horns. This is all
it is. Mhm.
>> And what we're seeing now, beloved, is
absolutely stunning. As Christians, we
look at the Heritage Foundation. We look
at Turning Point USA. We look at Project
2025. And you guys, all of it is
converging
>> to this right here. and turning point at
least
when Charlie was alive and I'm sure now
they would say the same thing is that um
there were political figures in the
Bible. So being political using politics
to um to move the things of Christianity
is biblical.
>> So they would have
>> they have a they don't have a problem
with it.
>> They don't have a problem with it at
all. They wouldn't have a problem with
us saying what we're saying. Yeah. On
that level. And and now we hearing calls
for a Sunday law.
>> You guys, let me let me say this.
I got more slides here and I'm not even
going to cuz this is Daniel 11:40. This
is
Yeah. Yeah. We're We're Let me Let me
say this.
Let me say this.
We are
[clears throat]
we are in a place right now
where
there are a lot of people who don't see
where the train is going and they've
jumped on the train.
>> Where is he?
>> Maybe even saying, "Yeah, you know what?
Um, if
when the train really gets fast, then
I'll jump off.
Not understanding you guys, not
understanding that when a train picks up
momentum, you pick up momentum.
>> And it's hard to get off.
>> It's hard to jump off a speeding train.
And Ellen White talked about such a
train.
>> She said it seemed like the whole world
was on board. Mhm.
>> You guys um
a
>> as we track
>> I want to say something.
>> I just let me say this real. Okay.
>> This final abomination of desolation
which is Satan himself appearing as
Christ. Ellen White literally says that
>> she calls him Satan appearing as Christ
as the fin the final about everything
before was showing us listen every time
it happens it get the seven demons get
worse and worse and worse. The final one
is when Satan appears as Christ.
>> That's what wipes out paganism and
atheism. Nothing else is going to do it.
Mhm.
>> But when it happens, all those who have
been filling their hearts with lack of
compassion,
>> lack of mercy,
>> lack of caring,
>> who are more concerned with the laws of
a nation than they are with the laws of
God,
>> are setting themselves up
to ultimately have the same kind of
heart
>> that will attract them to the heart of
Satan.
>> And what I want to say is it depends on
who's breaking the laws of the nation
because
>> yeah,
>> if the Epstein files don't make you jump
off the train and you stay on the train,
>> I mean, just think about that, y'all.
When I said that we're we're willing to
like just give the pass,
>> you're on our side. All right, then it
doesn't matter. You're on our side. This
is exactly what the Christian world
>> this righteousness was not in you did
this wrong. Righteousness in is
>> if you
have this position,
>> then it doesn't matter what you do.
>> It doesn't matter how corrupt you may
be. it. And and listen, this is the kind
of Christianity that makes people vomit
and also might I might add makes God
vomit.
That's
>> from these. Yeah. From these 10 horns,
you guys,
there is so much for us to learn that I
believe we have missed and and maybe one
of the reasons why
we don't see and understand Satan's
moving in the way that he's moving
today. Mhm.
>> You can see it without understanding the
ten horns.
>> But I definitely believe that when you
understand the ten horns,
>> there is no way
>> that you can still be caught up and
deceived by what's going on around us.
>> And if you are, then we need to pray.
Mhm.
>> Because
Yeah. You don't want to get to the place
where it doesn't matter what the devil
does.
>> Right.
>> Right. You're just like, "Well, if he
does it on behalf of Jesus, then I'm
cool with it."
>> Right.
>> That's a scary place to be.
>> No conspiracy here, guys. No conspiracy.
This is all just history.
>> You can literally
go study this for yourself.
>> This is all just history.
>> And a denial
of the things that are happening before.
It's like Satan's saying, "Don't believe
your eyes."
>> That's what Satan says. Y'all, don't
believe what you see right in front of
you.
>> Yes. Don't. Yes, he is trying to do
that. And I think
us down or not us are people
who downplay
racism and how powerful that spirit is
and what it will and all it and all it
all it does is it's the same spirit that
Satan had in heaven. It's just pride
>> because to be racist you have to make
yourself better
>> than somebody else.
>> Yeah. But that spirit is so powerful in
a negative way,
>> but it's so powerful and to to down and
to think that
that is what Satan is using to bring all
of this about
um to just let you know how powerful
that element of pride is.
>> Yep. And and you guys, it's nothing new.
>> This is literally what the Jews did in
the days of Jesus. Mhm.
>> They were like, "Y'all are Gentiles,
>> we are better."
>> Yeah. Yeah. The Bible is full of racism.
>> Yeah. It you we are better than you.
>> Yeah. We're better than you.
>> And you see that carry through the 10
horns.
>> So you guys, um, that's it. I don't know
if there's going to be a part four.
>> Well, let's
>> We'll just see what happens. I'll let
you guys know if I see him go into his
>> He doesn't go anywhere. I just see him
mentally go somewhere and then some
stuff like this happens.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
>> So, we'll see what happens.
>> Yeah.
>> But, um you guys, I hope that this
study, that this series,
>> this three-part series has been
>> eyeopening for you. I hope it has been a
blessing. Mhm.
>> Um I hope you understand that you know
and people will say it anyway but I need
y'all to understand you guys that this
thing is the furthest thing. It is
political only in the sense that it is
prophetical.
>> Right?
>> Prophecy is revealing
Christianity mingled with politics.
>> Right? And those who hold Christianity
mingle with politics as a sacred cow are
very often the loudest ones to say
>> you're being
>> political.
>> Political,
>> you're being political. Y'all will get
these slides. The slides will be
available on my uh Patreon page. So,
please uh we'll put it in the um
yeah, we'll put it in the description,
but I'm also going to put it here just
so that you have it. Um please go and
join that. Uh I'm put in the wrong page.
>> You always have your photo theology on
your mind.
>> Mercy, you were lying when you said the
end the the big bomb was towards the
end. Yeah,
>> you weren't lying.
>> Yeah, it you could trace it, you guys.
>> We we actually trace it throughout.
There is no break in the line.
>> It literally what we see happening today
is the culmination
>> of of over six over 2,000 years.
>> And that's that's just crazy. That's
just amazing.
>> Um all right, so that's it you guys.
Um, any closing words? Any closing
words?
>> I'm just letting it process or marinate
in my mind. Um,
>> I think I've said everything, but it's
just amazing that I shouldn't say well,
yeah, amazing that
you would try I mean that you would have
racism and then cloak it with like not
just righteousness, but
>> horns of a lamb speak
>> like a drink. Yeah. So, I shouldn't have
said
>> I'm amazed. But that is what the Bible
says.
>> Wow.
>> America is American. I just made
>> Clint, I got your email. I did get it.
Um, and I I will respond to you. Okay.
>> I think I got three of them,
>> in fact. So, uh, I'll respond. I'll
respond. All right, guys. Well, uh,
that's it. We will um
>> Wow.
>> We will keep y'all in prayer as you keep
us in prayer.
>> And uh may God bless you. May you all
have a have a wonderful Sabbath. And uh
join us for church tomorrow.
>> Yes, definitely join us for church
tomorrow. Uh the Living Mana online
church. We start at 12 p.m. Central
Standard Time. That's when our uh
Sabbath school starts. Um, and it's it's
not we don't use the the quarterly. We
do have um actually a group that does
use the quarterly and um does the Bible
study with the quarterly. Um and then
the sermon usually is starting around
well divine worship service starts at
1:30 p.m. Central Standard Time. So
please come and check us out. And what
is your sermon about tomorrow? So, my
sermon tomorrow is called the
TransChristian Movement.
>> That's right. I did see that.
>> The TransChristian Movement and
>> and it's not what you think.
>> Yeah. And if you're like trans
Christian, I never heard of that before.
Um, you will hear it now. Uh, Mandy,
yes, I will put the link uh to the video
um in
>> You can't do it now.
>> Yeah, I'll put the link in the video uh
in the description. Okay. And and I'm
just I just got a I just got a text from
from uh from Terry. I'm going to say
this, you guys. I would highly suggest
if you want to equip yourself
with the ultimate prophecy curriculum.
Back to basics.
>> Matthew 24,
>> elephant in the room,
the story of the ten horns. Those are
all series on our page on our on our
YouTube page.
>> Power below. Yes.
>> And um
you guys binge watch those.
>> Yes.
>> Binge watch those.
>> Um
>> those are those are the only reasons why
I could track with you. I mean and
building. Yeah.
>> And you know what's amazing ate is as
I'm going through I'm just think about
back to basics Matthew 24 elephant in
the room and uh
>> they were all building the 10 horns.
They were building. They were all
building to this.
>> There's nothing in any of them that
contradict. Oh, well, you know what?
>> This was this way first. No.
>> Absolutely.
>> Everything just
>> stacks. So,
>> yeah.
>> You know, perfectly. And that's because
it's truth.
>> That's because it's truth. So, you guys,
if you have not seen these um and I
don't know if someone can put these in
the it's on it's on our YouTube page.
Um,
>> yeah, they can they can just and you can
if you forgot some of them because you
listed quickly, but you can always go
back after this is over and
>> Yeah.
>> and then just put those names in the
power of the lamb and
>> and what Yeah. What I'm going to do is
I'm actually gonna I'm actually going to
create a new playlist.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, and
>> yeah, that would be nice. So, it's easy
for everyone.
>> I'm going to do a new playlist and we're
going to call it What should I call it,
y'all? Um,
>> truth. I don't know.
I guess
>> I'll call it the prophecy curriculum.
>> Yeah, that's good.
>> The prophecy curriculum.
>> And I'll put all of them all together
and just
>> just binge them.
>> All right,
>> Tante.
>> Yes, I will since I've resting my vocal
cords mainly.
>> Let me say this, you guys. I know. I
know. I know. Let me just say this.
No, we're not to embrace paganism,
right? Like,
>> right,
>> in case anyone says, "Oh, you know, he's
saying you shouldn't talk about
paganism." Not what I'm saying at all.
What I am saying is that if the spirit
of God is not in you, your hatred for
paganism, for atheism means nothing.
>> Right?
If the spirit of God is in you, you will
not have a hatred for atheists and
pagans,
>> right?
>> Your goal will be not only to let you
let let the light shine so that others
can see God and glorify him through you
>> or glorify yeah him through you. It'll
be to win others. Mhm.
>> So if the spirit of God is not in you,
all I'm saying is don't think that
holding certain political positions
>> is making you righteous.
>> And this is the I can't believe we're
about to we're just about to pray. We're
just about to pray,
>> right? But
>> now I'm just
>> Well, I but and I
>> ready to go on. You cannot think that
righteousness by hate
is a thing
>> is real Christianity
>> because it's not.
>> It's not.
>> And also that spirit it's it's the
spirit of hate but also the spirit of
forcing.
>> Yep. Of hate
>> and force.
>> The spirit of force and the spirit of
pride.
>> All three things are of Satan.
>> Yeah. Pride for for um force for force
and hate.
>> Yeah.
>> All right.
And I just want to say this because you
know I always have to put my uh
therapist hat on too and just what I see
here. It's like those same spirits, and
I know we're talking about the ten horns
and and prophecy and all of those
things, but that that spirit
finds itself
can finds it does find itself
and how we raise
our children
>> as Christians. Yep.
>> I'm going to bring it home a little bit
closer in the Adventist church.
>> Meaning
>> our children are not born 7th day
Adventist. And then it's okay of course
to lead by example and to teach them the
things of the Bible. Um, and maybe it's
not even just children, but then but
just forcing being legalistic and
forcing and having that spirit of pride
like you're forcing them to do these
legalistic things, but they see the
pride in you.
>> Yeah.
>> And they see, you know, all and so it
just makes them like how the atheist or
how it made people become atheist.
>> And I'm not saying our children are
actually claiming, oh, we're atheist.
>> Yeah. But they are saying I don't want
to be a Christian like what I was raised
with or what I see.
>> You look like one of the ten horns,
>> right?
>> Because when you were talking about
that, my mind was just going like, "Wow,
I see that.
>> I'm against this. I'm against that. I'm
against that. I'm against that." But you
don't have the love of God in your
heart. That's that's
>> that's what our children or that's
that's what they see.
>> And that's that parable.
>> That's what impacts them.
>> That's that parable on a human level, on
a personal level,
>> right? The house is empty.
>> It's swept and garnished,
>> right?
>> But it's empty of the spirit of God. And
so many of us
>> have that
>> yet we know the right things to do. We
know the right things to eat.
>> It's swept and garnished,
>> but empty of the spirit.
>> I also want to say since we're are still
on and everyone hasn't gone off yet.
Some maybe have left already, but I just
want to say this before we pray. Not
only do I see that in um in raising the
children or because again I was a mental
health therapist at one of our
universities for three years and I just
got to spend a lot of time and then I've
been a pastor's wife for 27 years just
see a lot of time with Adventist young
people and just see where they're at and
kind of you know their experience. Um
but
also
um I see the same spirit
not just in the conservative movement in
the in in in our in our politics with
Christian nationalism but in church
>> but also in the church
>> because like if I have that same spirit
I'm righteous.
>> Well that's what I was just saying. We
can know the right things, eat the right
things, you know, have all the right
rules,
>> and yet not have Jesus in us.
>> So, as parents, we can look like horns,
>> right,
>> to our kids.
>> Yes.
>> Like, okay, you're against this, this,
this, this, and this.
>> And they don't,
>> but where's Jesus?
>> Right. And they some become atheists.
Most most don't. But they're but they're
not ex you know they're not accepting
Jesus in their heart for real because
it's like
>> a lot of people take the French horn go
the French horn route atheism.
>> Yeah.
>> That might be a whole sermon y'all. That
might be a whole those 10 horns and the
the different representations of like
>> because how many how many French how
many French horns do we have
>> because of what they've seen in
>> you know the spirit of the little horn
or the spirit of you know this horn or
this horn or this horn
>> your hatred for for for
so-called wickedness but at the same
time Yeah, that um
>> we're about to bring up and yeah we see
that in a lot of unfortunately like
so-called
>> present truth circles.
>> Yes,
>> it's a problem.
>> It is.
>> So Satan spreads his spirit in all
different forms in all he's just like
I'm going to I'm going to try to blanket
>> the earth with this spirit um in so many
different places in politics in our
churches. It's not just our religion.
I've said this before. Um when I first
became uh a therapist, I had and not
because I advertise as a Christian
counsel therapist, but people were just
coming in that had so much religious
trauma from denominations I've never
even heard of.
>> It's just in every form
>> and all over. So,
>> yeah.
>> Yes.
All right. I think we can pray now.
>> All right.
>> Now that we got everything off our
chest, which is probably not everything,
but okay. All right. Heavenly Father,
Lord, I want to thank you for this
evening. Um, I honestly did not know
where it was going until
maybe after I said nine, to be honest. I
thought nine when I said it, but I saw
that it was going in an even deeper way.
And Lord, I just thank you for this
study. I thank you for everyone who um
has been viewing with us here live. And
I just and I pray for those who are
going to watch it after uh we are off
the air, Lord. is that your Holy Spirit
would continue to be with all of us as
we continue to grow and to study. And
Lord, help us not to have that spirit,
that spirit of pride, that spirit um of
of hating those who are not like us and
definitely not that spirit of racism.
Lord, we ask all of these things in
Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen. Again, we ask that you just like
um the uh YouTube channel, Power Lamb
YouTube channel. And we also invite you
to church tomorrow, Living Mana Online
Church, 12:00 p.m. Central Standard
Time. And it's also on YouTube. It's on
this channel that you're watching. And
there's also a Living Mana YouTube
channel. So, we'd love to see you there
tomorrow. Have a good evening.
>> God bless you guys.